TING FURYAN

PRODUCT MANAGER & TECHNICAL BUSINESS ANALYST

Website: http://ting.furyan.co - Email: ting@furyan.co - Phone: 512-777-1183 - Leander, TX

PROFILE SUMMARY

Accomplished business analyst and entrepreneur able to achieve multiple goals given a solid grounding in technological possibilities and 7+ years in data analysis. History of delivering highly functional software product prototypes for identifying and mitigating challenges and risks to bring products to market. Quick to immerse in various projects to become a process domain expert and find solutions to produce actionable tasks that achieve results.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: R, SQL, HTML, XML, JavaScript, C++, Salesforce APEX, and BASH

Software: RStudio, REST APIs, Salesforce, Atlassian JIRA, MySQL Workbench, SQL Developer, Github

Other: Regex, JSON, Lean Startup Principles, Agile Methodologies, MySQL, Oracle 10.1

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Electric Ember, LLC

Co-Founder and Business Manager

Apr 2013 to Present

- Oversaw all payroll, invoicing, budgeting, bookkeeping, event coordination, and minor accounting duties
- Expanded e-liquid line into over 10 stores in central Texas and into stores out of state to grow revenue \$70k YOY
- Analyzed costs and profit margins for product line and optimized ordering volume for over 30% cost savings
- · Designed company logo, business cards for members, menu of flavors, and all marketing materials at conventions

Morningstar, Inc.

Senior Business Analyst / Product Manager

Jan 2014 to Present

- Developed the derived data product strategy, roadmap, prioritization, value proposition, and business case
- Translated the product roadmap into features and specifications refined and tested with customers (UAT)
- · Led effort to gather and document functional requirements from clients to detailed written specifications
- Communicated updates on multiple project status, work completed and in progress, next steps, risks, and KPIs
- Created data offerings from concept, to definition, planning, implementation and release for 40+ feeds
- Secured \$20k contract with a coveted multi-billion dollar pipeline client solely based on implied volatility product

Vendor Business Analyst

Sept 2011 to Jan 2014

- Procured new (~10/year) and maintained existing vendor relationships with 200+ global data providers
- · Provided ad-hoc and monthly reporting and auditing of client subscriptions per SLA with our data vendors
- Served as escalation point for difficult or unresponsive data partners to resolve client requests
- Marketed 15+ new data offerings and new vendor partnerships to raise clients' perception of company's value add
- Delegated challenging, but skill level appropriate tasks to 1 direct report and 3 cross departmental teams' interns

Senior Data Analyst

Apr 2010 to Sept 2011

- Crafted guide materials and hosted monthly trainings for local and remote international operations offices
- Sought out new applications and methods to improve the suite of tools available for teams' productivity
- Extracted and transformed detailed error log information into concise actionable steps for QA team

Data Analyst

Apr 2008 to Apr 2010

- Logged and monitored defects or bugs (~10/week) among 500+ feeds aggregated in data warehouse
- Performed root cause analysis of data issues and implemented process improvement to prevent repeated events
- Converted raw data into clean and conformable formats for database processing and delivery

Research Analyst

Nov 2006 to Apr 2008

- Resolved 60+ tickets monthly from clients and colleagues in a fast and professional manner
- Updated clients on the progress of resolving their support request on a continual and proactive basis
- Arranged Webex sessions across various departmental teams with clients to expedite resolutions

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Austin, TX

Bachelor of Arts in Economics, 2005

Languages: Fluent in Mandarin

Awards: Outstanding Performer Award for Morningstar, Houston Endowment Jones Scholar